good afternoon welcome to this session
下午好，欢迎参加本届会议
on introduction to modular development
介绍模块化开发
I'm Alan Bateman
我是Alan Bateman
I'm the JDK this is number two five
我是JDK，这是第二五
sessions that we're doing a java one
我们正在做一个Java会议
this year on on modules and JDK nine and
今年将介绍模块和JDK九
you did the first one this just before
你在这之前做了第一个
lunch I'm prepared for JDK nine that's
午餐我为JDK九准备了
repeated tomorrow of the other talks
其他会谈的明天重复
here are repeated as well I'll show a
这也是重复的，我会显示一个
slide at the end and with with reminders
滑动到最后并带有提醒
just a little bit about some of the
只是一些
background on what we call the
我们所谓的背景
modularity landscape and so that you
模块化景观，让您
have some idea what's going on for Java
了解一下Java发生了什么
C 9 so the module system itself is being
C 9所以模块系统本身
developed and through the Java community
通过Java社区开发的
process through jsr 376 and this is
通过jsr 376处理，这是
targeted for Java C 9 mark Reinhold
针对Java C 9标志Reinhold
sitting at the table here he leads this
坐在桌子旁，他带领着这个
GSR Java C 9 itself it has its own
GSR Java C 9本身也有它自己的
umbrella GSR and that will own the
伞式GSR，它将拥有
overall contents of the Java C 9 release
Java C 9发行版的全部内容
it will also own the marginalization of
它还将拥有
the platform so for the first part of
平台的第一部分
this talk I just want to spend a few
我只想花一些时间
minutes and talk about what it means to
分钟，并谈论这意味着什么
be on a modular platform so this margin
在模块化平台上，所以这个余量
graph that I'll show you is essentially
我要告诉你的图表本质上是
something that Java C 9 and we'll have
Java C 9和我们将拥有的东西
to standardize within open JDK we're
在开放的JDK中标准化
working on the implementation in project
从事项目实施
jigsaw that could be the reference
可以作为参考的拼图
implementation of the module system
模块系统的实现
there's a number of Jets or Java
有许多喷气机或爪哇
enhancement proposals they're all
都是增强建议
numbered if you google for them you'll
如果您为他们谷歌编号，你会
find them all that just that document
找到他们只是那个文件
all of the detailed implementation
所有详细的实施
choices and command line flags and
选择和命令行标志以及
everything else related to
其他所有与
implementation you'll find it all listed
实施，您会发现所有这些都已列出
in the undocumented in these Jets and
在这些喷气机中未记录的
update it as we go along the important
在进行重要更新时进行更新
thing to understand is that JDK 9 is not
要了解的是，JDK 9不是
completed yet it's not intended to ship
完成但不打算发货
until 2017
直到2017年
that's quite a few things that are
那是很多东西
undergoing design discussions and so
进行设计讨论等
there would be there would be changes
会有改变
before it chips no doubt so bear in mind
毫无疑问，所以请记住
that as we go through some of the
当我们经历一些
examples and in this presentation I
例子，在这个演讲中
split this into two parts I'm going to I
分成两部分我要去
really introduced modules in the second
在第二部分中真正介绍了模块
part but I want to start by talking
部分，但我想从谈话开始
about and saying that module development
关于并说模块开发
starts with a modular platform so I'm
从模块化平台开始，所以我
going to talk about what it means to be
要谈论成为什么意味着
running on a modular platform this graph
在模块化平台上运行此图
in quotes is where we were with the JDK
用引号括起来就是我们使用JDK的地方
back in the sort of JDK seven time frame
回到JDK的七个时间范围
this looks pretty horrible there's not a
这看起来很可怕，没有
lot to say about us this is where we
关于我们的很多话，这就是我们
were a couple of years ago before we put
是几年前，我们把
in the effort to actually break up the
为了真正地分手
JDK into a set of cohesive modules and a
JDK分为一组内聚模块和一个
lot of progress has been made on that
在这方面已经取得了很多进展
the only thing to point out on this this
对此唯一要指出的是
this this horrible slide with with with
这个可怕的幻灯片与
cycles and all sorts of weird
周期和各种各样的怪异
dependencies is even back then in the
依赖关系甚至可以追溯到
early days of marginalizing the JDK we
边缘化JDK的早期，我们
did identify that there had to be some
确实确定必须有一些
core module we called a base at the time
当时我们称为基本模块的核心模块
it's now called Java Basin in the
现在被称为Java Basin
current module graph and this is the
当前模块图，这是
graph that we have now for the standard
现在为标准提供的图形
modules are the java c modules these are
模块是java c模块，这些是
the modules that are named with a name
以名称命名的模块
starting with java dot something right
以Java点开头的东西正确
down the bottom you'll see Java dot base
在底部，您将看到Java点库
that is the core of the system that is
这是系统的核心
where Java data Lang that objects lives
对象所在的Java数据Lang所在的位置
there's a couple of things to say about
有几件事要说
this graph is is when you when you study
这个图是你学习的时候
it for a few minutes is you will see
几分钟，你会看到
that for the most part there is only one
在大多数情况下，只有一个
technology in each of the modules
每个模块中的技术
there's a couple of areas that aren't
有几个地方不是
completely clean but for the most part
完全干净，但大部分
one technology per module the graph is
每个模块一种技术的图表是
extremely hierarchical and that's partly
极度分层，这部分是
because we've got aggregator modules for
因为我们有用于的聚合器模块
profiles in there
那里的个人资料
and but it's also hierarchical because
而且它也是分层的，因为
we Mabel to do a clean separation of
我们Mabel要做一个干净的分离
head folk and headless you can actually
头头和无头，你实际上可以
take a subset of these Me's modules and
采取这些我的模块的子集，
have a completely headless system
具有完全无头的系统
another important thing about this this
与此有关的另一个重要的事情
graph is there are no cycles this is and
图是没有周期，并且
this is this is this is important when
这是这很重要
you get to some of the later
你以后去一些
presentations I'm on the module system
我在模块系统上的演示
and Alex's talk tomorrow under the hood
和亚历克斯明天的演讲
you'll get to hear more about this I've
您将获得更多有关此的信息
only shown you here the modules that are
仅在这里向您显示了
the standard module graph are as in the
标准模块图如
Java dot star modules there's also a set
Java点星模块也有一套
of modules for JDK specific their names
JDK的模块名称特定
are start with JDK dot something and I'm
是从JDK点开始，而我
not showing them here just to keep the
不要在这里显示它们只是为了保持
glass at the graph readable now let's
图上可读的玻璃杯现在让我们
take a JDK 9 build this is last week's
采用JDK 9构建，这是上周的
promoted build so every week there's an
升级版，所以每周都有
early access build of JDK 9 this build
JDK 9的早期访问版本
is build one three six so I'm just doing
是建一三六，所以我只是在做
Java dash version on it just to show
Java破折号版本只是为了显示
that it's real
那是真的
that didn't come out right to this I
那不是出于这个我
just do Java - er to run an existing
只需执行Java-即可运行现有的Java
application I randomly picked the J
应用程序我随机选择了J
editor text editor it's it's it's a text
编辑器文本编辑器是文本
that a editor that has been written in
已经写过的编辑器
the Java language it's been around for a
Java语言已经存在了
long time I have absolutely no idea
很长时间我完全不知道
whether the maintainer zuv of J edit
J的维护者zuv是否编辑
have to have tried out JDK 9 bills or
必须尝试过JDK 9账单，或者
not I tried it out and it just works as
不是我尝试过的，它只是作为
as it did in jdk age there's a few
就像在ddk时代所做的那样，
issues on some platforms but it just
在某些平台上的问题，但它只是
works at least on the Mac without any
至少在Mac上可以正常运行
issues the important point to take from
发布重要的观点
this is this is that that an application
这是一个应用程序
and maybe it's using a bunch of
也许正在使用一堆
libraries if using supported api's it
库，如果使用支持的API
should just work exactly as it did him
应该完全像他一样工作
in jdk age there are a few issues and
在jdk时代，存在一些问题，
they're covered in the prepare for JDK 9
JDK 9的准备工作涵盖了这些内容
talk that when I talk just before
当我刚才说话时
lunchtime so here I am just looks for
午餐时间，所以我在这里找
the most part now it looks just like a
现在大部分看起来就像
regular JDK let's look a little bit
普通的JDK让我们看一下
further I'm calling a commute a new
我还叫通勤者
command line option here - - list
命令行选项--列表
- modules what this option does Java -
-模块此选项对Java的作用-
list modules is it lists down the
列出模块是否列出了
modules that are in the runtime image I
运行时映像I中的模块
showed of a graph a few minutes ago I've
在几分钟前显示了一个图表
repeated it here on the right side of
在此处右侧重复
the slide and what you're getting here
幻灯片以及您要在这里得到的
is just a list of all of the modules
只是所有模块的列表
that are in the runtime image and that's
在运行时映像中
just to show that this that it is the
只是为了证明这是
system is actually made up of these
系统实际上是由这些组成的
modules I can go further and I can give
模块，我可以走得更远，我可以给
to list modules a module name and it'll
列出模块的模块名称，它将
give me more information to describe
给我更多信息来描述
those modules I mentioned java-based a
我提到的那些基于Java的模块
minute ago it's the core of the system
分钟前，它是系统的核心
so if you can read this in it it says at
因此，如果您可以阅读其中的内容，
the top Java - list module space Java
顶级Java-列出Java模块空间
dot base so I'm asking this asking the
点基，所以我问这个问题
the runtime to list the Java dot based
列出基于Java点的运行时
module and what you see here is a bunch
模块，您在这里看到的是一堆
of exports and these are expressed in
出口，这些都用
terms of package names
软件包名称的条款
the core module exports java.lang Java
核心模块导出java.lang Java
Oh
哦
Java net and all these other core
Java Net和所有其他核心
packages of the system that's what
系统的软件包就是
java-based does it clearly defines these
基于Java的是否明确定义了这些
are the supported packages and the api's
是受支持的软件包和api的
and the types are in those packages that
类型在那些包中
you can use which have a base I'm taking
您可以使用我正在接受的基础
another module here the Java desktop
Java桌面的另一个模块
module the Java desktop module is the
Java桌面模块是
module where we have grouped all the
我们将所有分组的模块
headful api's the the graphical user
headful api是图形用户
interface not JavaFX more the
接口不是JavaFX的更多
traditional in WT and swing api's so
WT和swing API的传统
when you look at the list of exports for
当您查看出口清单时
Java desktop you see java.awt all the
Java桌面上您将看到java.awt
other there's a whole bunch of other sub
其他还有一大堆其他子
packages in the AWT or java.awt
AWT或java.awt中的软件包
namespace you'll also see javax.swing
命名空间，您还将看到javax.swing
and a bunch of other Ruy ones so it's
还有很多其他的Ruy，所以
got exports exactly as Java base has and
完全按照Java基础进行了导出，并且
just different set of packages right
只是一套不同的包装
down the bottom is the requires each of
底部是每个
the modules in the runtime describes
运行时中的模块描述
what its dependencies are the Java
它的依赖性是Java
desktop module requires Java base
桌面模块需要Java基础
everything requires Java base we'll see
一切都需要Java基础，我们将看到
this as we go through the presentation
在我们通过演示文稿时
it requires java xml there are some some
它需要java xml，有一些
of the api's and for persisting beings
的API和持久存在
and things that are based on XML there's
还有基于XML的东西
a Java prefs because the jet the there's
Java偏好是因为喷气式飞机
part of the use the the api's can store
API可以存储的部分使用
preferences and there's the data
偏好，有数据
transfer API that's that's the one that
传输API就是那个
exports the the DWTS data transfer API
导出DWTS数据传输API
so the important thing to is is that I
所以重要的是
could go through every one of the
可以经历每个
modules in this graph and I could get
该图中的模块，我可以得到
this get specified them to to list
这个被指定给他们列出
modules and I could see exactly what
模块，我可以确切地看到
api's did they export and what other
api他们出口了吗
modules do they they depend on another
它们是否依赖其他模块
little thing as part of this
作为这件事的一部分
introduction I just want to mention the
简介我只想提及
Java linker mark showed this in the
Java链接器标记在
keynote and where he used the Java
主题演讲以及他使用Java的地方
linker to create a small runtime that
链接器以创建一个小的运行时
only had the Java base module I think it
我认为只有Java基本模块
was it was a 64 bit image and I think it
这是一个64位的图像，我认为
was
原为
compressed down to 17 megabytes so what
压缩到17兆字节
the Java linker is is a tool that links
Java链接器是链接的工具
a set of modules and creates a runtime
一组模块并创建运行时
image in the in the earlier talk today I
在今天的早些时候的演讲中，我
talked about the modules completely blur
谈到模块完全模糊
the historical distinction between what
两者之间的历史区别
we know was the Jerry and the JDK the
我们知道是杰里和JDK
Jerry was just the run time in the past
杰瑞只是过去的运行时间
the JDK was the run time plus tools in
JDK是运行时加上工具
the past now we now that everything is
过去现在我们现在一切都在
broken into modules you can combine them
分为模块，您可以将它们组合
in different ways you can even link your
您甚至可以用不同的方式链接您的
own modules in and I'll show this later
拥有自己的模块，我将在稍后显示
in the presentation
在演讲中
to create your own run time an image
创建自己的运行时图像
that you can actually distribute that
您可以实际分发
runtime image and has has a bin
运行时映像，并具有一个bin
directory where you'll find tools like
您将在其中找到类似工具的目录
the Java launcher it has a comfort
Java启动器，它很舒适
rectory which has the configuration this
具有以下配置的直肠
is user editable configuration and then
是用户可编辑的配置，然后
there's other other parts of the runtime
运行时还有其他部分
image that are not intended to be edited
不应编辑的图像
so let's run the the linker command just
所以我们只运行链接器命令
to just if you have to didn't see this
就算你没看到这个
in the keynote just to show what
在主题演讲中只是为了展示
actually happens so in this lick Galen
真的发生了，所以在这个舔盖伦
command + J link is the name of the
命令+ J链接是名称
linker I give it a module path which is
链接器我给它一个模块路径是
just think of it as the directories on
只是将其视为目录
the file system where it will find the
将在其中找到文件系统
modules I'm telling it to add that
我告诉模块添加
module named Java desktop I show that
我命名为Java桌面的模块
module in the slide a couple of minutes
幻灯片中的模块几分钟
ago and I'm going to generate us into a
以前，我将使我们成为一个
directory called my image and then once
目录称为我的图像，然后一次
that turns for a couple of seconds I'm
转动了几秒钟
then going to type Java that lists
然后输入列出的Java
modules on that generated runtime image
该生成的运行时映像上的模块
and I see in there that it produced a
我在那里看到它产生了一个
runtime image with only five modules if
如果只有五个模块，则运行时映像
you remember a few minutes ago I showed
你记得几分钟前我展示了
the Java desktop module and at the end
Java桌面模块以及最后
is had this requires Java base required
有这需要Java基础吗
XML required data transfer and so on
XML所需的数据传输等
these are the modules that have been
这些是已经
linked together to produce this runtime
链接在一起以产生此运行时
image now we go back to our little J
现在我们回到小J
editor example that I used in one of the
我在其中之一中使用的编辑器示例
first slides I'm going to use Java - gr
我将使用Java的第一张幻灯片-gr
j edit and I'm going to run the J editor
j编辑，我将运行J编辑器
and with this small runtime that I've
有了这个小的运行时间
produced so if I only got platform
生产，所以如果我只有平台
in this one time mark in image that I've
在这个图像中，
created and I can use this to run my
创建的，我可以用它来运行我的
existing application so that is a that
现有的应用程序，因此
is a huge step forward for distribution
是分销的一大进步
because you can distribute a small
因为你可以分发一个小
runtime with your application so that's
应用程序的运行时，因此
a quick summary of part one and which is
第一部分的简要概述是
we've moved from this huge big monolith
我们已经离开了这个巨大的整体
that horrible big lots of dependencies
那可怕的大量依赖
and cycles in the graph we've moved to a
和图中的周期，我们已经移至
set of mostly cohesive modules each of
每个主要是内聚模块的集合，每个
the modules has a clear set of exports
这些模块具有清晰的导出集
we saw two examples and dependencies if
我们看到两个例子和依赖关系，如果
you if you stay on the class path
你，如果你继续上课
forever until you retire you will still
永远退休，直到退休
be using modules whether you know it or
使用模块，无论您是否知道
not because the platform itself is is is
不是因为平台本身就是
is modular and I've quickly just shown
是模块化的，我很快就展示了
you the the jailing tool to create your
您是创建您的
own runtime image and with a small
自己的运行时映像，并带有一个小的
subset of the platform modules so that
平台模块的子集，以便
the tag line from this is modular
标签线是模块化的
development starts with a modular
开发从模块化开始
platform that's part one out of the way
平台的一部分
I now want to start right back at the
我现在要从头开始
beginning and introduce what modules are
开始并介绍什么是模块
particularly how you would actually go
特别是你实际去的样子
and write a module yourself we start
并自己编写一个模块，我们开始
with the concepts and start building up
与概念，并开始建立
and writing our own modules so this is a
并编写我们自己的模块，所以这是一个
very intently introduction to modules a
非常专心地介绍模块
mess assuming that you've never seen
假设你从未见过
them before so starting with the basics
他们先从基础开始
every module has a name in the previous
每个模块在前面都有一个名称
slides you shall Java basis on Java
在Java上以Java为基础滑动
desktop we saw a couple of more Java dot
在桌面上，我们看到了更多的Java点
star modules in this example my module
在此示例中，星形模块为我的模块
is gone then I'm going to start with is
走了，那么我要开始的是
called stats dot core assume that it's a
所谓的统计点核心假设它是一个
statistics library that fan I'm going to
我要去的粉丝统计数据库
be making into a module the code in a
将模块中的代码制作成一个模块
module is organized by packages in this
这个模块是由软件包组织的
example assume my module has two
示例假设我的模块有两个
packages comm Acme stats core clustering
软件包comm Acme统计核心集群
cluster a sorry clustering and comm
群集一个遗憾的群集和通信
Acme stats core regression these are the
Acme stats的核心回归是
packages that my code is organized in
我的代码所在的软件包
this module I
这个模块我
just listed out to sample type names
刚刚列出样本类型名称
there to give you an idea of types that
在那里给你一个类型的想法
might be in this module in addition to
可能在此模块中
Java code my module may have resources
Java代码我的模块可能有资源
it may have native code it may have
它可能有本机代码
configuration
组态
it may have commands we're not going to
它可能包含我们不打算使用的命令
get into all of this in the introduction
在介绍中了解所有这些
but it your module may have those as
但它你的模块可能有那些
well the modules self description is
模块的自我描述是
expressed in a source file called module
用称为模块的源文件表示
- info Java that is the module
-作为模块的信息Java
declaration by convention this source
按照惯例声明此来源
file is placed in the root directory of
文件放置在的根目录中
your source code for the module so it's
您的模块源代码，因此
like being right up at the top the
就像在顶部
syntax for a module declaration is
模块声明的语法是
module space and then the module name
模块空间，然后是模块名称
and then we open curly brackets close
然后我们打开大括号关闭
curly brackets we flesh this out in over
大括号，我们将其充实
the next couple couple of slides we will
接下来的几张幻灯片，我们将
assume that our our stats core module
假设我们的统计核心模块
has a dependency on guava for this
对此有番石榴的依赖
presentation assumes guava is a module I
演示文稿假设番石榴是我的模块
express that dependency with a requires
用需求表达这种依赖
Clause so in my module declaration it
因此，在我的模块声明中
says requires guava if I start building
说如果我开始建造需要番石榴
up a module graph on the right side of
在右侧的模块图
the office of the the slide as we go
幻灯片所在的办公室
along we see a dependency on guava the
我们看到了对番石榴的依赖
module will add in a second dependency
模块将添加第二个依赖项
will assume that it depends on the Java
将假定它取决于Java
sequel module so this is a platform
续集模块，所以这是一个平台
module if you looked at the module graph
模块，如果您查看了模块图
ice I showed earlier on Java sequel was
我之前在Java续集上展示的冰是
actually in there you just we went
实际上在那儿，你只是我们去了
through it quickly we didn't look at all
通过它，我们没有看到所有
of the modules assume that the Java
的模块假定Java
sequel module is the module that exports
续集模块是导出的模块
the Java sequel API or the JDBC API is
Java续集API或JDBC API是
it sometimes known now we start a build
有时我们现在知道开始构建
up a module graph here we've got our
在这里的模块图，我们有
we've got our three our three modules
我们有三个，三个模块
and so we've got we've got our stat
所以我们有了统计
score we've got our guava I'm going to
分数，我们要加番石榴
add one more module to the to the module
向该模块中添加另一个模块
graph assume that we have a stats
该图假设我们有一个统计数据
see ally module command-line interface
请参见盟军模块命令行界面
assume it's it's a some kind of
假设这是某种
command-line tool that makes use of the
命令行工具
stats core module and we assume sorry I
统计核心模块，我们对此感到抱歉
may may have introduced that in the last
可能在最后介绍了
slide this is the module that has the
幻灯片这是具有
dependency on Java SQL so we've gone a
对Java SQL的依赖，所以我们走了
number of modules that's called append a
称为附加模块的数量
service that CLI depends on on stats
CLI取决于统计信息的服务
core and Java sequel stats core depends
核心和Java续集统计核心
on guava every module depends on Java
在番石榴上每个模块都取决于Java
base whether they declare it in their
根据他们是否在自己的声明
module declaration are not because
模块声明不是因为
everything ultimately is is is a
最终的一切都是
java.lang object now let's start
现在让我们开始java.lang对象
fleshing out this out a little bit more
充实一点
and we start looking at the Java sequel
然后我们开始看Java续集
module if I were to do a list modules
模块，如果我要列出模块
Java sequel I would actually see that it
Java续集我实际上会看到它
depends on java xml and a jet depends on
取决于java xml和jet取决于
java logging the dependency on java xml
java记录对Java xml的依赖
might be a surprise but if you look
可能会令人惊讶，但如果您看
closely in the java sequel package
在Java续集包中
you'll actually find there is the it's
您实际上会发现有
ports and storing and xml in in
端口和存储以及xml in
databases so therefore it depends on the
数据库，因此它取决于
XML API when one module depends on
一个模块依赖时的XML API
another module then we say that that
然后我们说另一个模块
module reads the second module so this
模块读取第二个模块，因此
is important is is the stats core module
重要的是统计核心模块
depends on guava we say the stats core
取决于番石榴，我们说统计核心
reads guava stat CLI depends on stat
读取guava统计信息CLI取决于统计信息
score we say that stat c-like reads m
得分，我们说stat c-like读m
stat score this readability relationship
统计得分这种可读性关系
which we build up over the next couple
我们在接下来的几个中建立
of slides is actually the basis for
幻灯片实际上是
reliable configuration that marked
标明的可靠配置
mentioned in the in the keynote so now
现在在主题演讲中提到了
let's take a little subset of the module
让我们来看一下模块的一小部分
graph and we'll just look at stat CLI
图，我们只看stat CLI
depends on Java sequel which ultimately
取决于最终的Java续集
depends on java logging we add a little
取决于Java日志，我们添加一点
bit of code to this so you can get an
一点代码，这样您就可以
idea as to what code might be in those
关于那些代码可能是什么的想法
modules
模组
it may be that let's see so let's start
让我们看看吧，让我们开始吧
with Java sequel first so it exports the
首先使用Java续集，以便导出
Java SQL package there's a type in that
Java SQL包中有一种类型
package called driver anyone that sees
看到驱动程序的软件包
JDBC probably has heard of Java SQL
JDBC可能听说过Java SQL
driver there's a method in in there it's
驱动程序中有一种方法
a public method public class that
一个公共方法公共类，
returns a logger instance it's called
返回一个称为的记录器实例
get parent logger let's suppose up in
让父记录器让我们假设
stat CLI we've got some code that
stat CLI，我们有一些代码
creates a Java sequel driver and then
创建一个Java续集驱动程序，然后
invokes its get parent logger and then a
调用其获取父记录器，然后调用
load method so you've got some method
加载方法，所以您有一些方法
invocation chaining actually going on
调用链实际上正在进行
here so how is this actually going to
这到底是怎么回事
work stat CLI only depends on Java
工作状态CLI仅取决于Java
sequel therefore only reads Java sequel
因此，续集仅读取Java续集
what's happening with these types in the
这些类型在发生了什么
in the logging module that stat CLI
在stat CLI的日志模块中
doesn't know anything about if there is
一无所知
nothing there's nothing in the code that
没有什么在代码中什么都没有
immediately tells you that it's using
立即告诉您它正在使用
the logging module now one way we could
日志记录模块现在是我们可以使用的一种方法
do this is as we could we could change
这样做是因为我们可以改变
stats eli's module declaration to have a
stats eli的模块声明有一个
dependency direct dependency on java
对Java的直接依赖
logging that will work but it would be a
日志记录将起作用，但这将是一个
little bit disappointing as a user of
有点令人失望的用户
java sequel i do not know about all of
Java的续集我不知道全部
us are as a user of java sequel i don't
我们是Java续集的用户，我不是
know anything about what its
对它的内容一无所知
dependencies might be so the module
依赖关系可能是模块
system helps with this by introducing
系统通过引入
and modifier called transitive so in the
和修饰符称为可传递的，因此在
jdk 9 public bills this is actually
jdk 9公共账单这实际上是
called public in the early access build
在早期访问版本中称为public
for jigsaw is called transitive I
因为拼图被称为传递我
mentioned earlier on about JDK 9 not
前面提到的关于JDK 9的不是
being final but this is what the current
是最终的，但这是当前的
proposal is and what's in the jigsaw
提案是什么，拼图中有什么
early access bills so in the Java sequel
早期访问费用，因此在Java续集中
module and it's module declaration says
模块及其模块声明说
requires transitive Java logging what
需要传递Java日志记录
this means is that anyone that depends
这意味着任何依赖
on Java sequel rial will read
在Java续集里亚尔将阅读
Java logging so what so what we build up
Java日志记录又如何构建
now in a few seconds the readability
现在只需几秒钟的可读性
graph I'm stat CLI I require Java sequel
graph我是stat CLI我需要Java续集
therefore I read Java sequel Java sequel
因此，我阅读了Java续集Java续集
doesn't requires transitive and Java
不需要传递和Java
logging therefore stat CLI reads Java
记录日志，因此stat CLI读取Java
logging in alex is under the hood they
登录alex是在他们的幕后
talked tomorrow he will go through a lot
明天他会经历很多
more on this but this is what the
更多关于这个，但这就是
readability graph is so I started the
可读性图是这样，所以我开始
black the black edges in the graph just
仅使图形中的黑色边缘变黑
think of it as a dependency graph when I
当我将其视为依赖图时
start adding the arms edges I've built
开始添加我已经建立的手臂边缘
up here a readability graph that takes
这里的可读性图
into consideration the requires
考虑到需求
transitive or implies readability as as
传递或暗示可读性为
we call it ok so that's that that's
我们称之为确定，那就是
readability the next thing I want to
可读性我想做的下一件事
look at is is exports and then combine
看是出口然后结合
things together to show how the supports
一起展示如何支持
and accessibility so in addition to a
和可访问性，因此除了
module having a requires clauses it can
具有require子句的模块可以
also have exports clauses we saw that
也有出口条款，我们看到
with Java base we saw that with Java
在Java基础上，我们看到了Java
Java desktop our module stats core will
Java桌面，我们的模块统计信息核心将
export to packages that suppose it
导出到假定的软件包
exports the clustering and the
导出聚类和
regression package that I showed in one
我在其中展示的回归软件包
of the one of the first slides let's
第一张幻灯片中的一张让我们
suppose there is also an internal
假设还有一个内部
package it's not part of the stats cores
包，它不是统计核心
API that package is calm acne stats core
该程序包是平静痤疮统计数据核心的API
internal essentially what we've done is
内部基本上我们要做的是
we've divided the types and the packages
我们已经划分了类型和包装
in this library into two those that are
在这个库中分为两个
part of its public API and those are
是其公共API的一部分，
internal nothing outside of that module
该模块之外的内部内容
is intended to make use direct use of
旨在直接使用
them that it elects they're over the
他们选择他们超过了
comm Acme stats core internal makes it
comm Acme stats核心内部实现了
this is a visual indication on this
这是对此的视觉指示
slide to say none of the types in that
滑动以说不出任何类型
package are accessible outside of the
包可以在
module now let's combine it with
现在，我们将其与
readability that we saw a few minutes
我们看了几分钟的可读性
ago stat CLI reads stat core remember it
之前stat CLI读取stat核心记住了
doesn't require so therefore it reads it
不需要，因此它会读取它
if that's chlorines sorry if stat CLI
如果那是氯，抱歉，如果stat CLI
reads stat score then it can access any
读取统计信息分数，然后它可以访问任何
of the public types in packages exported
导出包中的公共类型
by stat score it cannot read any it
根据统计得分，它无法读取任何内容
cannot access any types in the internal
无法访问内部的任何类型
packages because they're not exported so
软件包，因为它们没有被导出
this is a two-way street
这是两条路
I read the module and the other module
我阅读了该模块和其他模块
exports some packages and that allows me
出口一些包裹，这让我
to access the public types in those
访问那些公共类型
packages if if the if stat CLI does not
如果if stat CLI没有，则打包
read stat score nothing in that module
在该模块中读取统计信息得分没有
is accessible
可以访问
none of the public types not even in the
没有一个公共类型，甚至在
exported packages are accessible so this
导出的软件包是可访问的，因此
is important to get if it reads it the
读取它很重要
public types and the exported packages
公共类型和导出的包
are are accessible if it doesn't read it
如果不读就可以访问
they're not accessible so the big take
他们无法访问，所以很大
from this design and is that public no
从这个设计，那个公众没有
longer implies accessible this is a
不再意味着可访问，这是一个
significant significant change to the to
的重大变化
the platform but it's because we're
平台，但这是因为我们
retrofitting modules and to a mature
改造模块并走向成熟
platform and this is the this is this is
平台，这是这个，这是
this is how we do it with minimum
这就是我们最少要做的
disruption okay there are the basic
破坏好了，有基本的
concepts I now want to go through some
我现在想通过一些概念
of the commands or take questions at the
命令或在
end and as to how we're actually going
结束以及关于我们的实际走向
to compile modules and how we're going
编译模块以及我们将如何进行
to package them how we're going to run
打包它们，我们将如何运行
them I want to go through some of the
他们我想经历一些
commands to do all of these things we'll
命令来做所有这些事情，我们将
start with our stats core module and we
从我们的统计核心模块开始，我们
are going to compile it so there's I've
将要编译它，所以我已经
got a bunch of source code that's
有很多源代码
organized in a directory called SRC
组织在名为SRC的目录中
stats core
统计核心
important thing from this directory
此目录中的重要内容
structure to understand is I've put the
要理解的结构是我已经把
module name into the file path at the
模块名称插入文件路径
top level directory of the module source
模块源的顶级目录
code I've got the module declaration and
代码我有模块声明和
also under stats core I've got all the
在统计核心下，我已经拥有了所有
other classes that are for for all the
适用于所有
types that are in this module when I
当我在这个模块中的类型
compile it I get a class file for every
编译它，我得到每个的类文件
one of the Java files it's the familiar
熟悉的Java文件之一
and thing that we see where the output
我们看到输出的东西
directory written reflects the the same
写的目录反映相同
structure and the same class files as as
结构和与之相同的类文件
you see in this in the source directory
您在源目录中看到的
ignoring additional classes that might
忽略可能
get generated for inner classes and so
为内部类生成等等
on the Java C command that I'm using
在我正在使用的Java C命令上
here has a couple of options that you
这里有几个选择
may not have seen before the first is
可能在第一个之前没有看过
the is is the - - module path this is
是--模块路径是
the option to the compiler to tell it
编译器告诉它的选项
where to find dependencies remember our
在哪里找到依赖项，请记住我们
stat score depends on guava where's it
统计得分取决于番石榴在哪里
going to find the guava module it's
将要找到的番石榴模块
going to find it on the module path so
要在模块路径上找到它
for the examples as we build up here
对于我们在这里建立的示例
assume that we have a directory of
假设我们有一个目录
modules in in the directories named EM
名为EM的目录中的模块
lip and we'll work through all of these
唇，我们将通过所有这些工作
as as we go along so I'm just running
随着我们的前进，我就在跑步
one Java C command and I'm compiling all
一个Java C命令，我正在全部编译
of the source code for this module and
此模块的源代码
into an output directory so a couple of
到输出目录中，所以
things just to say about module path is
关于模块路径仅需说的是
that when I'm resolving dependencies I'm
当我解决依赖关系时
going to find the these dependencies on
将要找到这些依赖
the module path the module path is not
模块路径模块路径不是
equal to the class path it doesn't
等于它没有的类路径
suffer the all of the problems that the
遭受所有的问题
class path that there's no splitting of
没有分裂的课程路径
packages there's a whole bunch of issues
包里有很多问题
that the class path had we've learned
我们已经学会了上课的路
from all of those and have come up with
从所有这些，并提出了
a much more reliable mechanism which is
一个更可靠的机制是
the module path so when you were finding
模块路径，所以当您发现
modules you search download the module
您搜索的模块下载模块
path as before and they can be packaged
与以前一样的路径，可以将它们打包
in different form they can be exploded
它们可以以不同的形式爆炸
if there's two modules in the same
如果同一模块中有两个模块
directory then
然后目录
the module system will give up it's not
模块系统将放弃它不是
making a choice as to which which which
选择哪个
module you're looking for you have to
您要寻找的模块
fix those kind of issues so it's not
解决这类问题，所以不是
it's this is actually very simple we
这实际上是非常简单的
wouldn't go through some of this in the
不会在
the hack session on Wednesday I'll give
我将在星期三的黑客会议上
a link to that later on to show how the
稍后的链接以显示
module path is and how it works
模块路径是及其工作方式
the important thing is to understand is
重要的是要了解的是
that that's where modules are found and
那就是找到模块的地方
it doesn't suffer the same problems as a
它不会像
class path so now we're going to we'll
上课的路径，所以现在我们要
go and compile another module this time
这次去编译另一个模块
we'll compile stat CLI so we've already
我们将编译stat CLI，因此我们已经
compiled and the the stats core module
编译和统计核心模块
that's compiled into the mods directory
编译到mods目录中
we're now going to compile the stats Eli
我们现在要编译统计数据Eli
stats Eli requires stat score and we're
统计Eli需要统计得分，我们
giving a module path this time with two
这次给出两个模块路径
directories and because this time we
目录，因为这次我们
want to be able to find the stat score
希望能够找到统计得分
that we've compiled into the mods
我们已经编译到mod中
directory as before you've gone from a
目录与以前一样，已从
tree of Java files and you've generated
Java文件树，您已经生成了
with the compiler a tree of class files
与编译器一起使用一类类文件
so the module info gets compiled as
所以模块信息被编译为
before from from source into its binary
从源到二进制之前
form which is module info dot class now
现在是模块信息点类的表单
we've compiled our two modules that's
我们已经编译了两个模块
core and stats CLI let's run see the
核心和统计信息CLI，让我们来看一下
stat CLI code as a module so this is our
stat CLI代码作为模块，所以这是我们的
command to run it now the first thing is
现在运行它的命令第一件事是
is I pull the trick here we've got a
我在这里把戏，我们有一个
short form of module path which is - P
模块路径的简称--P
so broader and having big long
如此广泛，长久以来
command-line option I've replaced - -
我已替换的命令行选项--
module - path with - P because that is
模块-带有-P的路径，因为那是
the short form what you find in JDK 9 is
在JDK 9中找到的简短形式是
the new arc a lot of the new options
新弧很多新的选择
have a long form and a short form I've
我有一个长格式和一个短格式
switched to the short form and in this
切换为简写形式
slide I'm also using another short
幻灯片，我也在用另一个短片
option - M I'm telling it what the main
选项-M我告诉它主要的
module is this will initially look a
模块是这个最初看起来
little bit for both will shorten this as
两者的一点都会缩短
we move through this through the next
我们通过下一个
few slides - M tells me tells tells the
几张幻灯片-M告诉我告诉告诉
runtime what the what the initial module
运行时什么初始模块
is and what the main class is so there's
是什么，主要是什么，所以有
two portions to this where will it find
它的两个部分将在哪里找到
the stat CLI module it'll find it on the
stat CLI模块，它将在
module path it'll load that module and
模块路径，它将加载该模块并
it'll locate the entry point
它会找到入口点
here which is calm acne stat CLI main so
这里是平静痤疮统计CLI主要所以
we're actually executing code in the
我们实际上是在
module with with this command and that
该命令和那个模块
little prompt welcome to stat CLI we'll
提示及时，欢迎使用stat CLI
just assume that's what the the these
只是假设这就是这些
two runs when you restart now let's see
现在重新启动时运行两次，让我们看看
what's actually going on here so when I
这里到底发生了什么，所以当我
type that command what actually went on
键入该命令实际发生了什么
so remember this is this is our
所以记住这是我们的
dependency graph from a few minutes ago
几分钟前的依赖图
stat CLI dependent stats course it also
统计依赖CLI的统计课程
depends on on stats SQL as I said
如我所说，取决于统计SQL
earlier every module depends on Java
早先每个模块都依赖Java
base so therefore you have a edge and
基础，因此您有优势
from stat CLI to Java base here's the
从stat CLI到Java base，这是
full when I compute the transitive
当我计算可及性时已满
closure this is the full dependency
关闭，这是完全依赖
graph as before this actually happens at
像以前一样实际发生在
startup when you typed Java - M because
键入Java时启动-M因为
what happens is when it's attempted to
发生的是什么时候尝试
resolve the stat CLI module it's like oh
解决stat CLI模块的问题，就像哦
that depends on stat scored therefore
这取决于统计得分，因此
I've got to resolve that module that
我必须解决那个模块
depends on guava and so on so what
取决于番石榴等等
you've actually computed at startup when
您实际上是在启动时计算的
I type Java - M is I've actually
我输入Java-我实际上是M
computed the transitive closure in fact
实际上计算了传递闭包
has actually gone further it's actually
实际上已经走得更远了
computed to the readability graph
计算到可读性图
remember the readability graph I've
记住我的可读性图
added these additional engines because
添加了这些其他引擎，因为
of the requires transitive
的需求传递
so at startup when I did Java - Ian the
所以在启动时我做了Java-Ian
the runtime has produced this runtime
运行时产生了这个运行时
graph and resolved all of those modules
绘制并解析所有这些模块
to ensure that they're there there they
确保他们在那里
can all be located on the module path or
都可以位于模块路径上
in the runtime image so this is actually
在运行时映像中，所以实际上
what happens at startup so I can't
启动时会发生什么，所以我无法
actually start up if something is
如果某事真的开始
missing if I attempted to startup with
如果我尝试启动时缺少
guava missing then I would get an error
番石榴丢失，然后我会得到一个错误
at startup if you want to see more as to
在启动时，如果您想了解更多有关
what happens at startup there's a
在启动时会发生什么
there's a diagnostic option on the java
Java上有一个诊断选项
launcher which would print a little
启动器会打印一点
trace we're gonna have to work on the
跟踪我们将不得不在
trace a bit better in jdk 9 but this is
在jdk 9中追踪得更好，但这是
a subset of what you would actually see
您实际看到的内容的一部分
when you attempt to that command that I
当您尝试执行该命令时，我
did in the in the previous slide except
在上一张幻灯片中做了
you get trace information as if locates
您将获得跟踪信息，就好像找到了一样
modules where does it locate them y and
它在哪里定位它们的模块
y as well
y也是
right so everything so far I've compiled
是的，到目前为止，我编写的所有内容
and I've run but when I want to compile
我已经跑了，但是当我想编译的时候
things
东西
everything's exploded on the file system
一切都在文件系统上爆炸了
if I looked in the mods directory I see
如果我在mods目录中看到
stat score and I see lots of class files
统计成绩，我看到很多课程文件
that's a very inconvenient way to to
这是非常不方便的方式
distribute an application or a library
分发应用程序或库
as just a bunch of class files I want to
作为一堆我想要的类文件
package it up into a jar file and we
将其打包成一个jar文件，我们
have this notion of a modular jar a
具有模块化罐子的概念
modular jar is just a regular jar file
模块化jar只是常规的jar文件
but it has a module in for that in the
但是它在其中有一个模块
top directory the top-level directory
顶层目录顶层目录
and that that allows it to be to be used
这样就可以使用它
in other ways I'll talk about that in a
以其他方式我将在
few minutes but if you see a jar file it
几分钟，但是如果您看到一个jar文件
has a module introduction the top-level
有一个模块介绍顶层
directory it is a modular jar file so
目录是一个模块化的jar文件，因此
what I'm going to do on this car is I'm
我要在这辆车上做的是
using some of the newer options with the
在其中使用一些较新的选项
jar tool to create a modular jar from
jar工具，用于从中创建模块化jar
what I compiled previously so stats I'm
我之前编译过的内容，所以我
using this one to come to package up
用这个来打包
stat CLI the modular jar I'm going to
stat CLI我要去的模块化jar
create is is I'm going to create it into
创建是我要创建到
the EM Lib directory and I'm going to
EM Lib目录，我将转到
name the jar file stats CLI dot jar as
将jar文件统计信息命名为CLI dot jar作为
part of packaging up stat CLI I'm going
我要打包stat CLI的一部分
to specify what the main class is if
指定主类是什么
you're used to producing a an
你习惯于制作一个
application jar then you used to be able
应用jar，然后您曾经能够
to you're probably familiar with the the
对您可能熟悉的
main class attribute this is sort of the
主类属性这是
equivalent for modules and I can
等价于模块，我可以
configure this with the with the main
与主要配置
class option to the jar tool so what
jar工具的类选项
this does is this is all of the class
这是所有的课程
files that are in the mods that CLI I'm
我在CLI所在的mod中的文件
going to package them all up create one
将它们打包在一起创建一个
jar file stat CLI and that's on the
jar文件状态CLI，该文件位于
right the jar tool has a whole bunch of
正确的jar工具有很多
new options in in JDK 9 I'm going to
JDK 9中的新选项
just show you one of them here if you
如果你在这里给你看一个
find a jar file you can actually you can
找到一个罐子文件，您实际上可以
you can give the name of the jar file
您可以提供jar文件的名称
for our file patch of the jar tool and
对于我们的jar工具文件补丁
give it the option print module
给它选择打印模块
descriptor what that does is is is
描述符的作用是
it will give you it will describe the
它会给你它将描述
module that's in that jar file in this
这个jar文件中的模块
case it's our stat CLI module we can see
这是我们的stat CLI模块，我们可以看到
what does it depend on and and the stats
它取决于什么以及统计数据
Eli has no exports it's just it's a tool
Eli没有出口，只是一种工具
it's got no exports and it has a main
它没有出口，而且有一个主要
class so the jar tool is able to print
类，因此jar工具能够打印
that out so that's that's useful and
那是有用的，
when you get a bunch of jar files you
当您得到一堆jar文件时，
want to figure out what what modules are
想弄清楚什么是模块
in them okay now we've got our our stat
在他们里面好吧，现在我们有了我们的统计数据
CLI has been packaged up it's in the EM
CLI已打包在EM中
Lib directory I'm now starting to shrink
库目录我现在开始缩小
down like my my Java command a little
像我的Java命令一样
bit by just giving it the name of the
只是给它一个名字
initial module a few minutes ago I had
几分钟前的初始模块
my I specified - - m2 values the name of
我指定的--m2值
the main module and the main class now
现在的主要模块和主要类别
that I've packaged up the module I've
我已经打包了我已经打包的模块
the module now knows what its name class
该模块现在知道其名称类别是什么
is I don't need to specify that anymore
是我不需要再指定了吗
so my command shrinks down I can just
所以我的命令缩小了
tell it what the main module is - M
告诉它主要模块是什么-M
stats that CLI and it it will load the
该CLI及其加载的统计信息
main class from that module and
该模块的主要类别，以及
everything will get resolved as as
一切都会像
before
之前
okay I haven't I've talked a little bit
好吧，我还没有谈过一点
about the module path and we're used to
关于模块路径，我们习惯于
the class path and one thing to be aware
上课的路径和一件事要注意
of is you can mix them it is possible to
的是您可以将它们混合在一起
have to start or to compiler to run with
必须启动或编译器才能运行
some code already as modules and some of
一些代码已经作为模块，另外一些
the code on the class path you can
您可以在类路径上的代码
combine them together now the code and
现在将它们组合在一起，代码和
the modules of course can't depend on
模块当然不能依赖
anything that's on the class path or
任何在课程路径上的东西
what you might want to do and
您可能想做什么
particularly for migration is is is run
特别是对于迁移是运行
code on the class path but you're making
类路径上的代码，但您正在
use of libraries that have already been
使用已经存在的库
migrated to modules so this is where you
迁移到模块，因此您可以在这里
could where comes about where you will
可以从哪里来
want to combine the module path and the
想要结合模块路径和
class path together
一起上课
so the orange little box here is that's
所以这里的橙色小盒子是
GUI assume that's that's that's that's a
GUI认为那是那是那
graphical tool that makes you self this
图形工具，使您自已
that's core API that I'm that I'm using
那就是我正在使用的核心API
the maintainer of that has not got
那个的维护者还没有
around to migrating that code yet to a
到处将代码迁移到
module you want to keep it on the class
您想要将其保留在课程上的模块
pad for now because hasn't got around to
暂时填充，因为还没到
this yet all of the other libraries that
这是所有其他图书馆
are used in this system are already
在这个系统中已经使用
modules stats core has been migrated by
模组统计资料核心已由
us in this session it makes use of guava
我们在本届会议上利用了番石榴
we've been assuming that's already being
我们一直以为那已经是
migrated before before this session
在此会议之前迁移
starts and we have a couple of platform
开始，我们有几个平台
modules so how am I gonna run this these
模块，我将如何运行这些
two together and here's a sample command
两个在一起，这是一个示例命令
so I'm using - M I'm sorry - P short
所以我在用-M对不起-P short
form again of the module path I'm give
再次形成我给的模块路径
me the envelope directory where we've
我的信封目录
got all of our modules in there so we've
我们所有的模块都在那里
got our guava we've got our stat score
得到了番石榴，得到了统计数据
we've got other modules in there and I'm
我们还有其他模块，我
using - jar stats GUI jar so this is
使用-jar stats GUI jar，所以这是
where the main class for the stats
统计资料的主要类别
uie application is
UIE应用程序是
there is there is nothing in stats goig
没什么可统计的
are to say that it depends on the module
就是说这取决于模块
stat score this is just a jar file it
stat成绩这只是一个jar文件而已
has no dependency information I have to
没有我必须的依赖信息
I have to tell the system and that's
我必须告诉系统，那就是
what this add modules option is here
这个添加模块的选项在这里
this this application I'm going to run
这个我要运行的应用程序
is making use of a module stats core so
正在利用模块统计信息核心
by combining these two together my main
通过将这两个结合在一起
class is on the class path no dependency
类在类路径上没有依赖性
information I have to tell the system
我必须告诉系统的信息
that I need the stats core module to be
我需要统计核心模块是
resolved so that is the reason for the
解决，所以这是
stat the add modules stat score if stats
统计添加模块统计得分，如果统计
Gy was migrated to a module then its
Gy迁移到一个模块，然后将其
dependency information means that the
依赖信息意味着
system would know to be able to resolve
系统将知道能够解决
stat score but there's nothing when I
统计分数，但我什么也没有
keep that code on the command line now
现在将该代码保留在命令行中
let's get back to linking so ignore what
让我们回到链接，所以忽略什么
we wore with the stats GUI library for
我们使用了stats GUI库
now I'm going to start producing a
现在我要开始制作一个
runtime image that has the stats CLI
具有统计信息CLI的运行时映像
module so this is a module that we have
模块，所以这是我们拥有的模块
compiled packaged and now I want to go
编译打包，现在我要去
and create a runtime image for
并创建一个运行时映像
distribution I could just distribute it
分发我可以分发它
as a modular jar but assume that I want
作为模块化的罐子，但假设我想要
to be able to distribute a complete
能够分发完整的
runtime that doesn't have a dependency I
我没有依赖的运行时
don't want to have to ship a separate
不想不得不单独发货
JDK I just want to be able to reduce one
JDK我只是想能够减少一个
distribution with the jailing command so
用jailing命令分发
I run the jail in command I give the
我在命令中运行监狱
module path to and that tells it where
模块路径，并告诉它在哪里
to find the modules there's there's two
找到模块有两个
locations are giving to the module path
位置给出模块路径
one is where'd you find the platform
一个是您在哪里找到平台
modules and they actually are in the JDK
模块，它们实际上在JDK中
download where do I find the other
下载我在哪里可以找到其他
modules that's the EM Lib directory I'm
我所在的EM Lib目录中的模块
giving an ADD add modules to tell which
给一个添加添加模块来告诉哪个
modules to include in the runtime image
要包含在运行时映像中的模块
I want to include stats CLI and then I
我想包含统计信息CLI，然后我
give it an output directory which is the
给它一个输出目录是
location where of the the runtime image
运行时映像的位置
that I want to create
我想创造的
that turns for a couple of seconds and I
转动了几秒钟，我
get a runtime image that has one two
获得具有一两个的运行时映像
four seven modules in it at the
其中的四个七个模块
beginning of the presentation like I use
像我使用的演示文稿的开头
J link to create a runtime image with
J链接使用创建一个运行时映像
only platform modules now I'm using the
现在只有平台模块，我正在使用
the jailing tool to create a runtime
jail工具创建运行时
image that is a mix of platform modules
混合了平台模块的映像
and a number of my own modules that that
还有我自己的一些模块
I have written here so when I run Java -
我在这里写过，所以当我运行Java时-
list modules I get I see the names I see
列出我得到的模块我看到的名字
the Java based logging sequel XML if you
基于Java的日志记录续集XML（如果您
remember the dependency graph that I had
记得我有依赖图
earlier on these are those platform
这些平台上较早的是那些平台
modules you see there plus I said see my
你在那里看到的模块，我说看到我的
three of my own my own modules stat CLI
我自己的三个我自己的模块stat CLI
and stats and stat score so that's a
统计信息和统计信息得分，因此
sample
样品
jaelyn command in the advanced slot talk
进阶插槽中的jaelyn命令
later on today we will actually go
今天晚些时候，我们实际上会去
through will actually have a couple of
通过实际上将有几个
examples that have more complicated and
更加复杂的例子
interesting jailing commands and we can
有趣的jaail命令，我们可以
talk about it on Wednesday at hack
在hack上谈论它
session if anyone wants to come up and
会议，如果有人想站起来，
talk about that so that's that's that's
谈论那个，那就是那个
it so in this section we've got I've
所以在本节中，我们已经
talked through the basic the the the
通过基本的
basic concepts a module has a name it
模块的基本概念为其命名
expresses its dependencies it may have
表达它可能具有的依赖性
some it may have some exports you've
一些它可能有一些出口
seen how we've turned a dependency graph
看到我们如何变成依赖图
into a readability graphs you've seen
到您看到的可读性图中
the the notion of implied readability or
隐含可读性的概念，或
requires transitive and hope in this
需要传递和希望
quick introduction you've seen some of
快速介绍，您已经看到了一些
the the tooling and the image and the
工具，图像和
updates to the java c command the jar
更新到java c命令的jar
command the java launcher to be able to
命令Java启动器能够
give it a location of modules and so you
给它一个模块的位置，所以你
can see how to compile package and run
可以看到如何编译包并运行
with modules and that's it so so I said
与模块，就是这样，所以我说
at the beginning that we have five five
一开始我们有五个五个
sessions and so prepare for JDK 9 is
会议，因此为JDK 9做准备是
something we did just before lunch we
我们在午餐前做的事情
were pitting that tomorrow and the
在明天，
advanced modularity talked Alex and I
我和Alex和我谈过高级模块化
are doing that I think in this room
我正在这个房间里做
later on today at 5:30 and alex is doing
今天晚些时候在5：30，Alex在做
the services and the underhood talks
服务和秘密谈话
tomorrow and we've got a hack session on
明天，我们有一个关于
Wednesday at 8:30 if you want to bring
如果您想携带，周三8:30
along your laptop and try things out or
沿着笔记本电脑尝试尝试
just come along with questions so for
只是伴随着问题所以
more information as I said at the
如我在
beginning we're working on the
开始我们正在努力
implementation of this in project jigsaw
在项目拼图中的实现
this is the link to the project page the
这是项目页面的链接
mailing list and where we have the the
邮件列表以及我们拥有的
early access downloads and so if people
抢先下载，如果有人
have questions then please please come
有问题请拜托
up by Marc Rhino Liz is at the table
由马克·犀牛·利兹（Marc Rhino Liz）主持
here and I would hope will help answer
在这里，我希望会有所帮助
questions
问题
hello yes
你好
okay I'm curious about how JDK 9s module
好吧，我很好奇JDK 9s模块如何
approach compares to OSGi what would be
方法与OSGi相比会是什么
the advantages over using JD Ches module
使用JD Ches模块的优势
approach I - the dawn I might be on this
接近我-我可能会在此黎明
one hello yes
一个你好
right no he left okay never mind me oh
对不，他离开了，好吧，别管我哦
you're here so so so OSGi is is is more
你在这里，所以OSGi就是更多
than a module so I give you a very brief
而不是模块，所以我给你一个简短的
answer it's a deep topic Oster has much
回答这是一个很深的话题Oster有很多
more than a module system it's a
不仅仅是模块系统
security layer and a services layer and
安全层和服务层，以及
a bunch of other stuff and it doesn't I
一堆其他的东西，我不是
never reloading lots of fancy things
永不重装很多奇特的东西
which some applications need but many
有些应用程序需要但许多
don't the model system we're designing
不是我们正在设计的模型系统
for you know to be the standard model
因为你知道是标准型号
system for Java doesn't have all of
Java系统没有全部
those capabilities but it has a bunch of
这些功能，但它有一堆
additional capabilities namely you can
其他功能，即您可以
actually use it to modularize the
实际使用它来模块化
platform itself which you couldn't do
平台本身，你做不到
with those GIS guys built on top of Java
与那些基于Java构建的GIS专家一起
right and we need to modularize all the
正确，我们需要将所有
way down into it which is why modules
深入其中，这就是为什么模块
are a fundamental new program component
是基本的新程序组件
in this design rather than loading you
在这个设计中而不是加载您
know the class loaders with some fancy
熟悉类装载机
stuff around them so SGI works perfectly
他们周围的东西，所以SGI完美地工作
fine on top of nine and and that's is
九点就可以了，那就是
intended to keep working forever if you
打算永远保持工作，如果你
need to use it you know keep keep using
需要使用它，您知道继续使用
it it's a good solution for some
对于某些人来说这是一个很好的解决方案
problems but not for everybody that's
问题，但不是每个人都
that's the quickie answer I could fire
那是我可以开除的答案
up JVM and test this myself but it's
JVM并自己进行测试，但这是
easier to ask experts
更容易问专家
what happened lazy what happens if an
偷懒发生了什么
exported class tries to expose in the
导出的类尝试在
API and internal class that is not
API和内部类不是
exposed through the module to make sense
通过模块暴露出来很有意义
yeah your users will be unhappy well
是的，您的用户会很不高兴
will we will we get an error at compile
我们会在编译时出现错误吗
time or will that just be at runtime
时间还是只是在运行时
when the application craters so some of
当应用程序陷入困境时，
those cases can be ejected to detect
这些情况可以弹出来检测
at compile-time if they're not they will
如果不是，在编译时他们会
definitely be detected around them okay
肯定在他们周围被发现还可以
one thing just to keep in mind is is
要记住的一件事是
that it is very normal to have an API
有一个API是很正常的
that returns back some internal
返回一些内部
implementation that implements something
实现某些东西的实现
that is exported so this is it's it's
就是出口了，就是这样
very normal for me to and I was using
对我来说很正常，我正在使用
the Java sequel driver there for you to
Java续集驱动程序在那里，您可以
have a reference to a driver but it's
有一个驱动程序的参考，但这是
it's some internal I don't know Oracle
这是内部的，我不知道Oracle
database driver type that's in non
非数据库驱动程序类型
exporter package that that kind of thing
出口商打包那种东西
is normal I think what your scenario is
很正常，我认为您的情况是
is is what Mark was getting to where's
就是马克要去的地方
you make it you make an error in your
你犯错了
signature of your method and you end up
方法的签名，最终
having public driver in pull get driver
有公共驾驶员拉动驾驶员
or something like that and that's
或类似的东西，那是
something that can be detected at
可以在
compile time as long as the term as long
编译时间只要期限长
as the return type is available to
因为返回类型可用于
whoever's using your module way return
谁在使用您的模块方式返回
type could be defined in some other
类型可以用其他方式定义
module that's fine thank you I'm just
模块很好，谢谢，我只是
curious about the transitive
对可及性感到好奇
requirements how you determine what to
要求您如何确定
declare as transitive versus not how do
声明为可传递而不是不传递
you know what people are gonna need
你知道人们会需要什么
access to so the the simple answer is
访问，所以简单的答案是
and this actually relates to the
这实际上与
previous question if if you're we if you
以前的问题，如果你是我们，如果你
have an API that's that's using
有一个正在使用的API
basically types from some other module
基本上是来自其他模块的类型
in in its API you have a you have a
在其API中，您有一个
method that returns you know a type food
返回您知道食物类型的方法
that came from some to some completely
从某些到完全
other module then it's probably helpful
其他模块，那么可能会有所帮助
to your users for you to require
给您的用户
transitive that module if not they'll
如果不是，则传递该模块
have to do it themselves right make
必须自己做对
sense
感
I have the questions so we know we are
我有问题，所以我们知道
using Gradle 2 more too much manage the
使用Gradle 2过多管理
version right now so looks like modules
版本现在看起来像模块
company has to replace their Gradle so
公司必须更换他们的Gradle，所以
my question is I can see now we put
我的问题是我现在可以看到
everything into a jar at the module so
一切都放在模块的罐子里
is that something overlap when we should
当我们应该
using the module because that we don't
使用该模块，因为我们不
manage jars do either of us know enough
管理罐子，我们中的一个人是否足够了解
about Gradle to answer that question I
关于Gradle回答我的问题
think there's actually one or two Gradle
认为实际上有一两个Gradle
sessions that which actually talks about
实际谈论的会议
JDK and JDK 9 support Java 1 and so the
JDK和JDK 9支持Java 1，因此
module system doesn't replace Gradle and
模块系统不能取代Gradle和
I I think it'd be better to bring up
我认为最好提起
some of those questions at the Gradle
摇篮中的一些问题
sessions ok thanks in in general our our
会议好，总体上感谢我们
whole approach is to work it is to
整个方法就是工作
design something that will work well
设计一些效果很好的东西
with existing tools so it's designed to
使用现有工具的目的是
work well with maven and Gradle and and
与maven和Gradle以及
everything else we're not trying to
我们没有尝试的所有其他事情
replace those existing systems thank you
替换那些现有的系统，谢谢
thank you does j-link work
谢谢你做j-link的工作
cross-platform can I create a yes yeah
跨平台我可以创建一个吗
yes yes it does and we had a few issues
是的是的，我们遇到了一些问题
and what they believe have all been
他们相信的一切
resolved and does that mean that the
解决，这是否意味着
thing I did the final product that gets
我做的最终产品
produced will run on any platform or
生产的产品可以在任何平台上运行
does that mean I have to specify that I
这是否意味着我必须指定我
want to export to spark or to armor ok
想出口以产生火花或装甲好
jaelyn figures out what your target
杰琳找出了你的目标
platform is based on the platform
平台是基于平台
modules that you're linking in so if
您要链接的模块，如果
you're on Mac and you're and you give it
你在Mac上，而你又给它
a module path to a Windows distribution
Windows发行版的模块路径
then it it will actually link in the
那么它实际上将链接到
Windows versions of those modules and
这些模块的Windows版本和
produce you a Windows runtime that will
为您提供Windows运行时
only run on one Windows ok so it really
只能在一个Windows上运行就可以了
comes down to which Java base you point
归结为您指出的Java基础
out correct that that's it exactly
正确的就是这样
ok yeah Bob actually Mandy's her in the
好的，鲍勃实际上是曼迪在
front row is just pointing out that Bob
前排只是指出鲍勃
Vendetta who works on embedded gave a
从事嵌入式工作的Vendetta给了
talk but he actually his talk was this
说话，但实际上他的说话是这样的
morning where he actually was actually
他实际上所在的早晨
doing some demos of compile cross
做一些交叉演示
compiling are so cross-linking to
编译是如此交叉链接到
embedded platforms
嵌入式平台
I was learning how to hack my toothbrush
我正在学习如何破解牙刷
thank you so I have a question I related
谢谢，所以我有一个相关的问题
to immigration
移民
so you said from immigration purpose you
所以你说是出于移民目的
have option to use modular path and
可以选择使用模块化路径
cross paths at the same time and models
同时交叉路径和模型
will not be able to use libraries from
将无法使用来自
class bus but libraries from class bus
类总线，但类总线中的库
will be able to use classes from models
将能够使用模型中的类
right so if it depends on something I
对，所以如果这取决于我
cannot start to use models in my
无法开始在我的模型中使用模型
projects until guys till high school
项目，直到高中生们
these libraries will migrate them right
这些库将正确迁移它们
this is a really really good question
这是一个非常好的问题
and in our in our in our in our talk at
在我们的谈话中
5:30 we will be talking about migration
5:30我们将讨论迁移
and particularly Brown automatic modules
特别是布朗自动模块
that allow you to migrate to modules
允许您迁移到模块
without depending without waiting for
不依赖不等待
everyone else to move to modules first
其他人先移至模块
so come along to 5:30 we have a lot of
所以来5:30我们有很多
session a lot of slides on this exact
会议上有很多与此有关的幻灯片
topic does the module system solve er
模块系统解决问题
hell we we hope so that is that is one
地狱我们希望如此
of the primary goals and how does it do
主要目标及其作用
that
那
where you are in the room right right
你在房间的右边
but it didn't say any versioning besides
但是除了其他版本没有其他版本
maybe the at 9:00 to suggest that might
也许在9:00建议
be versioning oh well if if the solution
如果解决方案可以版本化哦
for jar hell you're looking for is it
对于罐地狱，您正在寻找的是
involves version numbers then no we're
涉及版本号，那么不，我们是
not solving that problem and that's and
没有解决那个问题，那是和
that's related to the answer he gave a
这与他给出的答案有关
minute ago about fitting in with
分钟前关于
existing tools so jerk jerk jar hell
现有的工具让混蛋罐混蛋
like any pejorative term has many
像任何贬义词一样
different meanings right the jar haw
罐子山楂有不同的意思
problem that with that we are out to
问题在于我们要
solve is the one of okay you've got a
解决是好的，你有一个
zillion jar files on the classpath I
我在类路径上的zillion jar文件
mean you know we've seen new Oracle
意味着您知道我们已经看到了新的Oracle
internal products with more than a
内部产品具有超过
thousand jars it's like wow does is he
一千个罐子，就像哇，是他
how does it even work you can't figure
怎么还算不出来
out what that you you can't tell when
告诉你什么时候你不知道
there are conflicts you can't tell them
有冲突你不能告诉他们
said things are missing you can't tell
说东西不见了，你不能告诉
when it's safe to replace something
什么时候可以安全更换
that's that's the particular form of jar
那就是罐子的特殊形式
hell
地狱
we're trying to to giveaway out of and
我们正试图从和
once you once you once you can get to a
一旦你一旦你一次，你可以去一个
same module graph then you have good
相同的模块图，那么你就有
answers to all of those questions and
所有这些问题的答案，以及
you don't have the chaos of the class
你没有班上的混乱
path now as two versions there there are
现在有两个版本的路径
are lots of reasons why we're not why
有很多原因为什么我们不是为什么
did this module system does not have
这个模块系统没有
versions in terms of it doesn't have
就它而言没有版本
version constraints you can stick a
版本限制，您可以坚持
version on a module as as basically its
基本上在模块上的版本
documentation and it gets carried around
文档，随身携带
will be reported in stack stack traces
将在堆栈堆栈跟踪中报告
and and things like that because it's
和类似的事情，因为它是
very useful to know well code came from
知道很好的代码来自非常有用
you know version of what of what module
你知道什么模块的版本
but there is no way and this is
但是没有办法，这是
intentional in the module declaration to
有意在模块声明中
say that you know this module acts
说你知道这个模块的行为
requires version one you know some
需要一个版本，你知道一些
version between 1.2 and 3.9 of why but
为什么在1.2和3.9之间的版本
but not know but but never to dot 4.1
但不知道但永远不会加点4.1
because I know because I know that
因为我知道因为我知道
what's broken right the very the very
到底是什么被打破了
early prototypes of jigsaw we we
拼图的早期原型我们
actually were solved we're trying to
实际上已经解决了，我们试图
solve that problem and we realized wait
解决了这个问题，我们意识到等待
a minute maven solves this problem
一分钟的专家解决了这个问题
Gradle solves this problem other system
Gradle用其他系统解决了这个问题
solve it solve this problem now maybe
解决它现在解决这个问题也许
they don't those existing systems don't
他们不是那些现有的系统
solve the problem in the theoretically
从理论上解决问题
optimal way but you know what millions
最佳方式，但你知道几百万
of people use these tools already and to
的人们已经在使用这些工具，并且
be and to try to displace that would
并试图取代那将
just be a fool's errand so this module
只是一个傻瓜的差事，所以这个模块
system works with the concept of the
系统符合以下概念
module path which is a way to find
模块路径，这是一种查找方法
modules and we would rely on your build
模块，我们将依靠您的构建
system whether it's whether it's maven
系统是否是行家
or Gradle or make files or you know take
或Gradle或制作文件，或者你知道
your pick to make sure that the correct
您的选择，以确保正确
versions of things you have are on that
你所拥有的东西的版本
path and just just add just even just
路径，只是添加甚至
something very very practical is suppose
假设一些非常实用的东西
you have a bunch of jar files on your
你身上有一堆jar文件
underpants path today that are either
今天的内裤路径是
different versions of the same library
同一库的不同版本
or the or happen to be using the same
或或恰好使用相同的
package or whatever it might be
包装或任何可能
try that with the module system and as
尝试与模块系统和
modules on the module path and it will
模块路径上的模块，它将
not allow these it will detect these
不允许这些它将检测到这些
kind of split package issues that's you
那种分包问题就是你
won't even start up it'll there if
甚至不会启动，如果
you've got issues there are if you've
你有问题，如果你有
got two versions of the same mod
有两个版本的同一国防部
and then it will pick whatever the first
然后它会选择第一个
one is and on your module path it will
一个是在模块路径上
never it will completely ignore all the
永远不会完全忽略所有
other versions that you might have so
您可能会有的其他版本
there's an you've got no scenario where
有一个你没有方案
to be trying to load some parts of quani
试图加载quani的某些部分
or example here come Acme stats core
或例子来这里Acme统计核心
from this jar file and more from it from
从这个jar文件中获得更多
this other jar file that just doesn't
这个其他的jar文件
happen with modules related to that if
发生与有关的模块，如果
you're mixing a class Pat back with a
您正在将班级Pat和班级混在一起
modular app so in your example you
模块化应用程序，因此在您的示例中
pulled in guava
拉番石榴
so if I have guava on the class path as
所以如果我在课程路径上有番石榴
well as embedded within a module okay so
以及嵌入到模块中就可以了
my module wins so if my app is the class
我的模块赢了，所以如果我的应用是班级
path app right in it it requires guava
路径应用程序就在其中，它需要番石榴
then it's pulling the version of guava
那就拉番石榴的版本
from the module so my app is on the
来自模块，因此我的应用程序位于
class path so it doesn't require
类路径，因此不需要
anything if there's nothing in in your
如果你什么都没有的话
Maya just say what it depends on so
玛雅人只是这么说
we're out of the box we assume that when
我们开箱即用，我们假设
you're running things on the class path
你在类路径上运行东西
that you just require any of the modules
您只需要任何模块
in the in the runtime images of export
在导出的运行时映像中
API okay but but I can also have a
API可以，但我也可以
dependency on a local jar file in the
对本地jar文件的依赖
class path that could be a guava version
可能是番石榴版本的类路径
right yes it could
是的，可以
so if I do that and then guava is also
所以如果我这样做，那么番石榴也是
packaged up in one of the modules then
然后打包在其中一个模块中
what happens so in that scenario
在那种情况下会发生什么
nobody requires guava because there's
没有人需要番石榴，因为有
there's no module that has requires
没有需要的模块
guava here and the your module path
番石榴在这里和您的模块路径
isn't even being looked at here unless
甚至不在这里看，除非
you give it an ADD modules to tell it
你给它一个ADD模块来告诉它
that you want the guava module to be
您想要的番石榴模块是
resolved so you might remember in the in
解决了，所以您可能还记得
the in in the slide we had to do enact
幻灯片中的我们必须制定
modules that's core in order to ensure
核心模块，以确保
that that module was resolved if you do
如果您执行该模块，则该模块已解决
that modules guava then the guava module
该模块番石榴然后番石榴模块
will be used the guava dejar and your
将使用番石榴dejar和
class path will be ignored
类路径将被忽略
to go back a little bit just to be clear
回去一点只是为了清楚
if I had to if I had a module depend on
如果我必须有一个模块取决于
two different modules and each of those
两个不同的模块，每个模块
modules is dependent upon a different
模块取决于不同的
version of a same module it's going to
相同模块的版本
kill it knock it out and say hey this
杀死它，把它敲出来，说嘿
isn't even allowed yes okay if they're
甚至不允许，如果他们是
you know if you're if you're doing
你知道你是否在做
something sophisticated like record
像唱片一样复杂的东西
writing an app server there's some
写一个应用服务器，有一些
advanced features of the module system
模块系统的高级功能
that let you support that kind of
让你支持那种
scenario but in practical use you know
场景，但在实际使用中，您知道
for for for smaller less sophisticated
用于较小的较不复杂的
applications which as most of them hit
他们中大多数都击中的应用程序
that better it's not needed you know in
更好的是，您不需要知道
generally if today you have two
通常如果今天你有两个
different versions of library on your
您的不同版本的库
class path you're already in trouble you
班级路径，您已经遇到麻烦了
just might not know yet
可能还不知道
so I had a question I had a question in
所以我有一个问题
regard to you had a slide where you made
关于您制作幻灯片的地方
a very strong statement that public does
公众强烈要求的声明
not mean accessible what about for like
并不意味着可以访问什么
reflection so can reflections still peek
反思，所以反思仍然可以偷看
under the hood and violate all your
在引擎盖下侵犯您的一切
system of trying to hide things cleanly
试图干净地隐藏东西的系统
so core reflection has been specified
所以已经指定了核心反射
for 20 years to do the same exactly the
20年做完全一样的
same access tricks as the language and
与语言相同的访问技巧
the VM and that and that continues so
虚拟机，并继续如此
with with strong cops at capsulation
有强大的警察在封装
then even your public typed in your non
然后甚至您的公众也输入了您的非
exported packages can't be broken into
导出的软件包不能被分成
with good core reflection so you have to
具有良好的核心反射率，因此您必须
explicitly export them in claire as a
明确将其导出为克莱尔
tenancy and if they support them to make
租约，如果他们支持他们
them reflect right exactly and there's
他们恰好反映正确，并且
also another concept on on the table I
桌上的另一个概念
didn't go through in the introduction
在介绍中没有经历
talk but Alex will touch on that today
说话，但亚历克斯今天会谈到
in the advance talk and that is sort of
在预先的谈话中，这有点
designed for especially for applications
专为应用而设计
and other libraries then that are
还有其他的图书馆
intended to be deeply reflected on by by
旨在由
other libraries so Alex will touch on
其他库，以便亚历克斯将接触
that this afternoon and the advance talk
今天下午和预告片
the quick teaser is is there's a way
快速的预告片是有办法的
that there's basically a way to export
基本上有一种出口方式
you can export a package and you can
您可以导出软件包，也可以
also say don't not only export a package
还说不仅要导出包裹
but let reflection get into my internals
但让反射进入我的内心
as well because I you no good because
也因为我你不好
you're expecting this module to be
您期望这个模块是
supported by you know JPA or something
您知道的JPA或其他支持
yep I think we're done here thanks for
是的，我想我们已经完成了，谢谢
attending thank you
参加谢谢